☆独家制作☆
喜马拉雅主播 & 微信公众号:
美国青少年英语
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
地球脉动 III
Much of our planet still remains unexplored...
我们星球上的很多地区仍未被探索
..for most of it is covered by water.
因为这些地区大部分都被水覆盖
Every journey below the surface can reveal something extraordinary.
每一次水中之旅都能揭开奇妙事物的面纱
More than a thousand new species are discovered here every year.
在这里 每年有超过一千种新物种被发现
The ocean is home to 80% of all animal life on Planet Earth.
海洋是地球上80%动物的家园
But today, thriving in this varied world
但如今 要在这个多变的世界中生存发展
sometimes demands the most surprising behaviour.
有时需要做出令人惊讶的行为
海洋
The shallow seas of the tropics.
热带浅海
This may look like a paradise...
这里看上去如天堂般美好
..but beneath the surface, it is an arena
但海面之下 是一个
for constant life-and-death struggles,
不断进行生死搏斗的竞技场
where not everything is quite as it seems.
隐藏在表面现象背后
A predatory lionfish...
掠食性狮子鱼
..on the hunt for shrimp and small fish.
正在寻找小虾小鱼
With so many places for its prey to hide,
有这么多地方可供猎物藏身
the lionfish has to be patient.
狮子鱼必须耐心下来
This shrimp appears tempting.
这只虾看起来很诱人
As the lion-fish closes in,
当狮子鱼靠近时
it fans out its fins to disorientate its prey.
它会展开鳍来迷惑猎物
The hunter becomes the hunted.
猎人变成了猎物
Tricked by one of the shallow sea's most extraordinary predators...
被浅海中最特别的捕食者之一摆了一道
..a clown frogfish!
大斑躄鱼
On its head, it carries a fishing rod –
它头上带着一根鱼竿
a modified dorsal fin,
是一种改良后的背鳍
baited with a lure - easily mistaken for a shrimp.
诱饵很容易被误认为是一只虾
But, when the fish stop biting,
但鱼都不上钩时
it's time to pack the rod away
就该把鱼竿收起来
and move on.
换个地方了
And, for a frogfish, that takes time.
对于躄鱼来说 这得花不少时间
Rather than swim, frogfish walk!
躄鱼不会游泳 反而只会走路
Its fins have, in effect, become feet.
它的鳍实际上相当于脚
It may not look pretty,
躄鱼可能看起来不漂亮
but what appears to be coral living on its skin is actually camouflage.
但看似长在它身上的珊瑚实际上是一种伪装
As every good angler knows,
每个钓鱼高手都知道
picking the right spot is important.
地点非常重要
Jigging the rod sends out pressure waves
摇动钓竿发出震动
to attract the attention of possible prey.
从而吸引猎物的注意
These dragonets are certainly interested.
这些鳜鱼被吸引住了
Almost there.
还差一步
Hook, line, and sinker.
彻底上钩了
Like all shallow seas, the cold waters off the coast of North America,
浅海往往受益于强烈的阳光
benefit from the intensity of the sunshine.
北美沿岸的冷水域也不例外
Here, that fuels
在这里 阳光
one of the fastest-growing organisms on the planet...
为地球上生长最快的生物之一提供了物质基础
..giant kelp.
巨藻
Towering forests can eventually reach the height
高耸的巨藻森林最终可以达到
of a 12-storey building.
12层楼的高度
These forests are nurseries for young horn sharks.
这些森林是幼年角鲨生长的温床
As the sun begins to set,
太阳落下时
they leave their daytime shelter
它们离开白天的庇护所
and set off into the heart of the kelp forest to find food.
前往巨藻森林中心寻找食物
Barely half a metre long, this little shark is extremely vulnerable.
这条只有半米长的鲨鱼非常脆弱
There are monsters here.
这里生活着巨兽
A giant sea bass –
一条巨大的海鲈
weighing over 200kg...
重达200公斤以上
..and wolf-eels, with big teeth
以及长着巨大牙齿的狼鳗
that can crush little red sea urchins.
能够咬碎小红海胆
But the biggest danger comes from other sharks -
但最大的危险来自其他鲨鱼
houndsharks...
皱唇鲨
..and huge broadnose sevengills.
以及巨大的扁头哈那鲨
In this forest, it pays to keep a low profile.
在这片森林中 最好是保持低调
An angel shark...
扁鲨
..one of the most deadly sharks in the kelp forest,
巨藻森林中最危险的鲨鱼之一
and certainly the best camouflaged.
也有着最高明的伪装
An angel shark will lie in wait for days...
扁鲨通常会潜伏数天
..but this one has already attracted too much attention.
但这条扁鲨已经吸引了太多的注意
It's not welcome here.
这里不欢迎他
Now, the coast is clear.
现在 危险解除
But angel sharks hunt around the clock.
但扁鲨是全天候捕猎
Openings for breathing, called spiracles, blow out sand that helps cover its body.
呼吸孔可以吹起沙子以掩藏身体
The trap is set.
陷阱已经布好
Staying close to the seabed is a good way to avoid most predators.
贴紧海底是躲避大多数捕食者的好办法
Faster than the blink of an eye.
迅雷不及掩耳
But it's not over yet.
但还没完
Horn sharks have a secret weapon.
角鲨有一种秘密武器
Sharp spikes keep them very much off the menu for most.
锋利的尖刺使它们得以幸免于大多数捕食者
So, this young horn shark can hunt in safety...
因此 这条年轻的角鲨可以安全地捕猎
..for now.
最起码暂时安全
Violent winter storms batter these kelp forests.
猛烈的冬季风暴扑向了这片巨藻森林
The plants can be ripped from the seafloor...
这些植物会被连根拔起
..and carried away far out to sea.
被海浪带向远处
The open ocean is a vast, featureless desert.
开阔的海洋是一片广袤无奇的沙漠
Even a small piece of drifting kelp can become valuable.
哪怕是一小片漂浮的海藻也会变得弥足珍贵
It's just what these fish have been searching for.
这正是这群鱼一直在寻找的东西
Here, shelter where eggs can be laid unobtrusively is rare...
在这里 不引人注目的产卵处十分稀少
..so they make the most of it.
因此要充分利用
Each female produces up to a thousand eggs,
每条雌性产下多达一千颗卵
and the males rush in to fertilise them.
雄性争先恐后使鱼卵受精
All this activity attracts the attention of blue sharks.
这些活动吸引了大青鲨的注意
They can travel thousands of miles
它们为了寻找食物
through the ocean in search of food...
可以在海中移动数千里
..and they may not have eaten for weeks.
而且这些大青鲨可能已经几周没吃过东西了
It seems that they're in luck.
似乎走运了
But these fish are no easy meal.
但这些鱼并不好抓
They are flying fish!
它们可是飞鱼
The blue shark, however,
然而这条大青鲨
are not here for the fish...
不是奔着鱼
..they have come for the caviar.
而是奔着鱼子来的
But flying fish lay so many eggs,
但飞鱼群产下的卵非常多
that the sharks' feasts hardly make an impact.
多到鲨鱼的盛宴几乎不会造成影响
And, in a few months' time, a new generation will take to the skies.
几个月后 新一代飞鱼又将在空中"展翅"
Floating islands of weed are always attractive to creatures
对于在大海中寻找居所的生物来说
looking for shelter out in the big blue.
漂浮的水草总是很有吸引力
But, in today's ocean, they are being replaced by something else...
然而如今的海洋中 取代水草浮岛的是
..plastic.
塑料
12 million tons of it end up in the ocean every year.
每年有1200万吨塑料最终流入海洋
The deadliest kind are discarded fishing lines and nets.
最致命的是废弃的渔线渔网
Each year, it's likely over half a million animals are ensnared
每年 约有50多万只动物
and killed by these "ghost nets."
被这些"幽灵网"困住并死亡
But some animals are learning
但有些动物在学习
how to take advantage of the plastic rafts...
如何利用这些塑料筏
..and use them for shelter, or even as a home.
将其作为庇护所 甚至作为家
This male Columbus crab – barely bigger than your thumb nail –
这只和拇指指甲差不多大的雄性哥伦布蟹
is a castaway.
漂泊无归
Clinging to his net,
它紧紧抓着网
he may have been drifting on ocean currents for months.
可能已经在洋流中漂流了数月
Now, fully grown, he needs to find a partner.
如今它已经长大了 需要找个伴侣
But where?
但哪儿找呢
Certainly not here,
肯定不是这儿
alone on the net.
这儿只有它孤零零一个
Columbus crabs are not good swimmers, so this male is marooned.
哥伦布蟹并不擅长游泳 因此这只雄蟹走投无路
Perhaps a passing loggerhead turtle could be the chance to hitch a lift.
也许一只路过的红海龟是个搭便车的好机会
Made it!
成功抵达
But there's more than one passenger here -
可这里还有别的乘客
a female Columbus crab!
一只雌哥伦布蟹
They waste no time in getting acquainted...
它们决定不浪费时间熟悉彼此
..and start to mate.
而是直接开始交配
This pair may well stay together for the rest of their lives.
这对哥伦布蟹很可能会一起度过余生
A turtle, after all, makes an excellent home.
毕竟 海龟身上是个完美的家
In return, the crabs provide an onboard grooming service.
作为回报 哥伦布蟹会提供甲板清洁服务
Finding a partner in the vast ocean is not easy.
在广袤的海洋中寻找伴侣并不容易
Dawn in the Sea of Cortez...
科提兹海 黎明之际
..Mobula rays.
蝠鲼
They're gathering here, most likely to breed.
它们聚集于此 很可能是为了进行繁育
No-one is sure why they leap,
蝠鲼跃出海面的原因尚不清楚
but the loud splashes certainly seem to attract more rays.
但水花飞溅的声音显然吸引来了更多的同胞
Other creatures, however, are also listening.
然而 听到声音的还有其他生物
Orca have heard the splashes.
虎鲸循声而来
This female specialises in hunting rays.
这头雌性虎鲸精通蝠鲼狩猎
But today, she is teaching two youngsters
但今天 它正在传授两头年轻虎鲸
the finer points of Mobula ray hunting.
狩猎蝠鲼的细节诀窍
The rays are fast and can outmanoeuvre an orca.
蝠鲼的速度很快 甚至快于虎鲸
She knows she needs to herd the prey into a tight group...
雌虎鲸明白它需要将猎物驱赶到一起
..but she can't do that on her own.
但这项工作无法独自完成
It will take teamwork,
而是需要团队合作
and that is today's lesson.
而这正是这节课的主题
The young orca are quick to catch on.
年轻的虎鲸理解的很快
The rays are surrounded.
蝠鲼群被包围了
They dive...
它们迅速下潜
..only to be forced back up again by the experienced female.
却被经验丰富的雌虎鲸逼回海面
And now, with the exhausted rays trapped against the surface,
精疲力竭的蝠鲼无路可逃
she attacks...
雌虎鲸发动进攻
..and the young ones follow her lead.
年轻虎鲸则紧跟它的脚步
This family are the only orca known to hunt rays like this...
这一家子是已知的虎鲸群中 唯一用这种方式捕猎蝠鲼的
..and they are lethally efficient.
而且效率十分之高
But it appears that school is over for today.
但似乎今天的课程到此为止了
For a few battle-scarred survivors,
这些幸存下来的伤痕累累的蝠鲼
it's a lucky reprieve.
可以暂时喘一口气了
With the orca gone, the rays can resume their courtship...
虎鲸离开后 蝠鲼群得以继续它们的求偶行为
..and they do so in astounding numbers.
而且规模惊人
Tens of thousands of rays in a single shoal.
数以万计的蝠鲼聚集在一起
Vast areas of our ocean are yet to be explored.
海洋中还有广阔的区域尚未探索
The least known parts of it are its great depths.
这之中最不为人知的区域是海洋深处
Only highly-specialised vessels can take you there.
只有高度专业化的潜艇才能抵达
As you descend, the sunlight rapidly fades.
随着越潜越深 阳光会迅速减弱
200m down, you enter the twilight zone...
200米深处 是一片黄昏世界
..an alien world, inhabited by creatures beyond imagination.
仿佛置身外星 超乎想象的生物生存于此
A siphonophore – with a cloak of lethal stinging tentacles.
管水母 身披一层致命的刺触须
Siphonophores repeatedly clone themselves
管水母反复地自我复制
and so grow to immense lengths.
不断生长 体长极长
This one measures 45m and is the longest animal ever recorded.
这一只达到了45米 是有记录以来所有动物中最长的
With such deadly predators around,
附近存在着如此致命的捕食者
creatures here go to great lengths to hide.
这里的生物因此不遗余力地隐藏自己
A glass squid...
玻璃鱿鱼
..completely transparent,
身体完全透明
except for its eyes...
除了眼睛
..and stomach,
以及胃部
so it is extremely difficult to find in the gloom.
因此它很难在黑暗中被发现
Below 1,000m,
1000米深处以下
all traces of sunlight have disappeared.
一缕阳光也无法照射进来
This is the midnight zone.
一片午夜世界
Catching food in the perpetual darkness is not easy.
在永恒的黑暗中捕捉食物十分困难
A gulper eel.
吞鳗
Its giant, extendable mouth
它巨大且可伸展的嘴部
can engulf prey larger than its own body.
可以吞下比自身还大的猎物
Two miles down, you finally reach the ocean floor.
再往下三公里 终于抵达了洋底
We know more about the surface of Mars.
相比于此 我们对火星表面的了解还更多一些
The pressure of the water is 300 times greater than at the surface...
这里的水压是海面处的300倍
..and it's freezing cold.
而且十分寒冷
Yet, amazingly, there are animals living here.
然而令人惊奇的是 依然有动物生活于此
Muusoctopus robustus,
Muusoctopus robustus
nicknamed the pearl octopus.
绰号珍珠章鱼
Breeding, in these extreme conditions poses
在这样的极端条件下繁殖
a particular problem for these animals.
给这种动物带来了一个特殊的问题
At these low temperatures,
在如此低温下
this female's eggs could take over ten years to develop.
雌性珍珠章鱼卵发育时间长达十数年之久
So she travels to a very special place.
因此它会前往一个特别的地方
This is the largest known gathering of octopus in the world.
这是世上已知的最大规模的章鱼聚集群
She joins 20,000 other females...
它与其他两万只雌性珍珠章鱼一起
..all here to lay their eggs.
来到这里产卵
Water, heated deep in the Earth's crust,
在地壳深处被加热的水
rises through cracks in the seabed...
从海底的板块裂缝中涌出
..raising the temperature to as much as 10 degrees Celsius.
将温度升高至10摄氏度
A deep-sea thermal spa!
形成一片深海温泉
This warmth significantly speeds up the development of their eggs.
温暖的水显著加速了珍珠章鱼卵的发育
Even so, they will still take nearly two years to hatch.
但尽管如此 小章鱼也需要近两年时间才能孵化出来
Once a female is settled,
一旦雌性珍珠章鱼安顿下来
she won't move from her spot...
它便再也不会移动
..not even to feed.
甚至不会进食
She will constantly tend to her brood –
它会一直照顾自己的孩子
keeping them clean,
保持孩子们的清洁
and oxygenating them with jets of water.
以及使用水流为孩子供氧
Pearl octopus mothers must surely be amongst the most devoted.
珍珠章鱼母亲是世上最无私奉献的母亲之一
After almost two years, the ordeal take its toll.
两年间 这份艰苦的工作对珍珠章鱼母亲的身体造成了严重的损伤
But the vigil is almost over.
但漫长的坚守也终于进入了尾声
The last of the brood are gently encouraged to leave.
珍珠章鱼母亲温和地鼓励最后一窝孩子走出家门
But this will be a final act.
这也用尽了它的最后一丝力量
Like all the mothers here, this octopus is starved and exhausted.
像每一只珍珠章鱼母亲一样 它已经饥寒交迫 精疲力竭
Her life will soon be over.
它的生命也走到了终点
But this devotion means that her offspring are among
但这样的无私奉献意味着它的后代
the largest and most developed of any octopus
将是所有章鱼中个头最大 发育最完善的
and have the best chance of survival
将在严酷的深海世界中
in the demanding world of the deep.
拥有最佳的生存机会
We're finding more of these strange hot springs every year.
每年我们都会发现更多这种奇异的热泉
In some places, they can be astonishingly violent.
在某些地方 热泉的剧烈程度相当惊人
Super-heated water – hot enough to melt lead -
足以融化铅的过热水
spouts from the seafloor.
从海底喷涌而出
Dissolved minerals condense around them
溶解的矿物质在热泉周围凝结
to form towering chimneys, known as hydrothermal vents.
形成高耸的烟囱状 被称为深海热液喷口
They are home to unique communities of animals
深海热液喷口是独特动物群落的家园
that all rely on the nutrients in the scalding water.
这些动物依靠滚烫的水中的营养物质生存
Some suggest that vents like these could be the places
有观点认为四十亿年前
where life on Earth first began four billion years ago.
生命正是起源于类似这样的喷口
And there is now evidence of hydrothermal vents
如今有证据表明 木星和土星的卫星上
on the moons of Jupiter and Saturn.
同样存在热液喷口
Could they too be supporting life?
它们也能孕育生命吗
Here on Earth, the influence of these vents
在地球上 这些喷口的影响范围
extends far beyond their chimneys.
远远不止于烟囱周围
The essential nutrients carried in these plumes
烟雾中携带的基本营养物质
can rise all the way to the surface two miles above.
可以一直上升至三公里之上的海平面
Here, they stimulate the rapid growth of tiny marine plants on an astronomic scale.
在这里 它们能极大的促进微小海洋植物的生长
This phytoplankton is so abundant that it produces half of all the oxygen on Earth.
大量的浮游植物产生了地球上一半的氧气
It's also food for a host of minute animals -
浮游植物同时也是许多微小动物的食物
zooplankton.
也就是浮游动物
Together, they are the basis of the food chains
它们共同构成了海洋中
that sustain nearly all life in the ocean.
几乎所有生命的食物链基础
In the Pacific waters off South America,
在南美洲附近的太平洋海域
they feed anchovy that gather here in billions.
它们是聚集在这里的数十亿条凤尾鱼的食物来源
This is one of the world's most productive ecosystems.
这是世界上生产力最高的生态系统之一
These South American sea lions are on the hunt.
这些南美海狮正在捕猎
But the anchovy shoal has already been located...
但这里的凤尾鱼群已经被发现了
..by the planet's most efficient hunters.
被地球上最高效的捕猎者捷足先登
A net, over half a mile long,
一张近1公里长的渔网
encircles the shoal.
将鱼群包围
It can trap over a million fish.
它能捕获超过一百万条鱼
But the sea lions aren't about to go hungry.
但这些海狮是不会空着肚子的
They have learnt to look for holes in the net.
它们学会了寻找渔网上的破洞
Why waste energy when food comes to you as easily as this?!
这么容易就能填饱肚子 何必还费劲捕猎呢
As more and more sea lions arrive,
随着越来越多海狮的到来
some change their tactics.
一些海狮改变了策略
They line up on both sides of the net...
它们排列在渔网两侧
..and wait.
然后静候佳音
As the net tightens, the anchovy panic and rush for the surface.
渔网收紧时 凤尾鱼惊慌失措 纷纷跃向水面
This is the moment the sea lions have been waiting for.
海狮等的就是这个时候
It's such an effective way of hunting that the sea lions here
这是一种非常高效的狩猎方式
are changing their natural behaviour...
这里的海狮正在改变它们天生的习性
..and are raiding the fishing nets
成千上万的海狮聚集在一起
in their thousands.
掠夺渔网中的凤尾鱼
With the net almost drawn in,
随着渔网被彻底收紧
the fishermen beat out a warning signal.
渔民们发出了警告信号
Time is up.
时间到了
In the confusion, not everyone manages to escape.
在混乱中 有些海狮没能成功逃脱
The trapped sea lions are in danger of being drowned.
被困在渔网中的海狮有被淹死的风险
Pups are separated from their mothers.
幼崽与母亲被迫分离
Then, at the last minute, the fishermen briefly drop their net...
在最后一刻 渔民们短暂的松开了渔网
..and the trapped sea lions can escape.
被困海狮得以逃脱
But many are not so lucky.
然而幸运获救的只是少数
Around the world, millions of animals are accidently caught
世界范围内 每天数以百万计的动物
and die in fishing nets every day.
被渔网意外捕获并最终失去生命
And this by-catch, as it's known,
这种被称为副渔获物的意外捕获
is pushing many species toward extinction.
正在将许多物种推向灭绝的深渊
Animals have evolved in remarkable ways
动物以非凡的进化过程
to the demands of life in the ocean.
逐渐适应了海洋生存环境
But can they now adapt to the new challenge -
然而如今面对新的挑战
living alongside us?
它们能适应如何与人类共存吗
幕后花絮
The open ocean is home to some of the largest
广袤的海洋是地球上一些最大的
and most extraordinary animals on Earth.
最特别的动物的家园
But here, off the Canary Islands,
但在这里 加那利群岛附近
the Planet Earth team are searching for one of its smaller,
「地球脉动」摄制组正在寻找海洋中一种体型较小
and less familiar residents.
不被人熟知的居民
We're looking for a tiny creature called a Columbus crab,
我们在寻找一种叫哥伦布蟹的小生命
which is only about the size of your thumbnail,
只有拇指指甲大小
which live on floating objects in the open ocean.
生活在海上的漂浮物体上
Columbus crabs were once only found on natural debris,
哥伦布蟹曾经只能在天然漂浮物上发现
like driftwood or seaweed,
比如浮木或者海藻上
but the oceans are changing,
但海洋一直在变化
and they've been forced to adapt.
它们不得不适应新的环境
The best place to find Columbus crabs
最容易从中找到哥伦布蟹的
is in plastic
是塑料
because around 90% of the things we see drifting are plastic
因为我们见到的漂浮物中有90%都是塑料
One of the most common items they find is discarded fishing gear.
最多见的漂浮物是废弃渔具
Over a million tons is left adrift in the ocean each year.
每年有超过一百万吨渔具被丢弃到海洋中
And Columbus crabs are now making their homes on these unnatural materials.
哥伦布蟹如今正以这些人造物品为家
There's a crab!
那儿有只蟹
Surprisingly, Columbus crabs are thriving on this new habitat.
令人惊讶的是 哥伦布蟹在这些新家中发展蓬勃
But, for larger ocean creatures, these nets can be lethal.
但对于较大的海洋生物来说 废弃渔网有着致命危险
Loggerhead sea turtles are especially vulnerable.
红海龟尤其脆弱
Many times, they are very injured
很多时候它们会因此身受重伤
and many times they don't even survive.
甚至往往失去生命
It's a sad situation.
现状很不乐观
As a rule, wildlife film-makers observe natural behaviour
通常来说 野生纪录片团队只应观察生命的自然习性
and do not interfere.
而不应加以干涉
But this is far from natural.
但这已远非自然习性
The team feel they must take action.
摄制团队认为他们必须采取行动
It seems that the turtle is quite OK.
看起来这只海龟情况还好
We'll just finish to cut the plastic and then we release it.
我们只需割开塑料 然后释放它
It's a bittersweet moment,
这是一个苦乐参半的时刻
as this is one of eight turtles they rescued whilst filming here.
拍摄中救出的多达八只海龟 这仅是其中之一
This situation is not natural,
这种情况不是自然的
it's something that is being caused by human beings.
而是人类造成的
Sadly, the crew now face dilemmas like this
遗憾的是 摄制组不得不在多个拍摄地点中
on many of their filming expeditions...
面对类似的窘境
..including, when they travelled to the Pacific coast of Chile,
包括前往智利太平洋海岸
to show how sea lions are competing for food with one of the biggest fisheries on Earth.
拍摄海狮与地球上最大的渔场之一争夺食物的场景时
Expedition leader Fernando Olivares takes the team to the fleet.
队长费尔南多·奥里瓦雷斯带领团队前往捕鱼船队
Diving near fishing nets is extremely dangerous,
在渔网附近潜水是非常危险的
so the crew must ensure they have the full cooperation of the fishermen.
因此潜水团队必须确保得到渔民的全力配合
Requesting permission to deploy divers outside the net?
请求在渔网外部署潜水员
Is that possible?
情况允许吗
Yes. Be extremely careful.
允许 千万小心
Thank you very much, Captain.
谢谢船长
Pretty hazardous place to dive.
在这潜水相当危险
It's just a case of trying to keep an eye on the divers,
这项工作需要时刻关注潜水员
but the sea lions also like to go down and blow bubbles,
但海狮也会潜下去呼出泡泡
so you'll think you're following the divers,
就有可能会发生你以为你跟着的是潜水员
and then a sea lion will pop up.
但其实是海狮的情况
Taking the utmost care,
为了最大限度的确保安全
the divers get a close-up view of the sheer scale of the operation.
潜水员仔细观察了这次行动的规模
This one net must have about 15 tons of fish in it
这张渔网里准有15吨的鱼
and there's eight or nine boats in this one little bay,
这个小海湾里有八到九艘船
and these are just the small boats.
这些只是些小船
Out there, there are huge factory ships that are taking even bigger catches.
在那边 有大船在执行更大规模的捕鱼任务
How much fish a year from just here?
这里一年能捕到多少鱼
From a million tons a year more or less.
每年一百万吨上下
The catches are so vast,
捕鱼量如此之大
the sea lions have changed their natural behaviour
海狮已经改变了自然习性
to collect anchovies directly from the nets.
直接从渔网中捕捉凤尾鱼
But it's a risky strategy.
但这种方式存在风险
The crew witnessed sea lions caught in nets multiple times.
船员们多次目睹海狮被渔网捕获
Whoa, it's intense mate, there are so many in there.
太惨烈了 渔网里太多了
There's a pup stuck in the net, calling to its mother,
有一只海狮幼崽困在渔网里 一直在求助母亲
and its mother's just on the outside of the net calling back.
但母亲除了在渔网的另一侧呼叫也无能为力
That's really hard to watch.
真的很不忍心
Oh, the pup's really panicking now.
海狮幼崽现在很慌张
Sometimes, fishermen are able to release trapped sea lions...
有时 渔民能够释放困住的海狮
..but not this time.
但这次不行
The pup is in serious danger.
海狮幼崽命在顷刻
Once again, the crew decide to step in.
摄制组再次决定采取行动
Hey, he's going to go inside of the net to save him.
嘿 他要进渔网里救那只海狮
Nice, really nice.
太好了 真的太好了
It's a relief this time...
这次可以松一口气了
..but it highlights the new realities of filming wildlife
但这也凸显了拍摄野生动物新的实际情况
in today's changing ocean.
在如今瞬息万变的海洋中
Next time, a journey to Earth's greatest wilderness -
下一集 茫茫荒野之旅
deserts and grasslands...
前往沙漠与草原
..where nature puts on its most dramatic show.
在这里 大自然上演动人心弦的精彩戏码
Habitat Explorer brings animals and their habitats to life.
「栖息地探索者」生动地展现动物和它们的栖息地
Explore this free interactive and make origami animals.
探索这个免费互动程序并制作折纸动物
Go to bbc.co.uk/planetearth3
前往bbc.co.uk/planetearth3
And follow the links to the Open University.
点击链接进入开放大学
Or to order a free printed version,
或者订购免费印刷版
visit the website or call the numbers on the screen.
欢迎访问网站或拨打屏幕上的号码